Anatoliy Yastreb

Software Engineer

+49 177 7817203

I'm a web software engineer with 5 years experience in eCommerce and overall 10 years of experience in web development. I have led teams of 3 to 4 developers and have experience in setting up team workflow according to industry's best practices.

I'm passionate about complete process of product development - from collecting requirements to deployment and impact analysis. I enjoy working with smart people, crafting software which brings value to customers, and continuously improving my skills.

Experience

Senior Software Developer at Luxury Fashion Trade GmbH (fashionette.de)

Düsseldorf, Germany, 2013 – 2016

Technologies: Magento, PHP, Laravel, Solr, Varnish, Microservices

Led development team of 3-4 in various projects, including new features implementation, payment methods integration and online shop localization in 16 new countries for Germany's biggest online designer handbags retailer.

Senior Software Engineer at Magento, X.commerce, Inc. (an eBay company)

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2011 – 2013

Technologies: PHP, SOAP WSI, REST, Redis, MongoDB, Gearman

Worked on Magento Core API, performed R&D on Magento 2 API platform. Participated in Magento Connect and Magento GO (SaaS) projects development.

Web Developer as Independent Contractor

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2007 – 2010

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, AWS, Solr

Implemented various projects, such as DiccionarioLibre.com, ProfileStar.com, MyCubi.com

Junior PHP Developer at eTek Systems

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2006 - 2007

Technologies: PHP, XML, Atom

Worked on international customer's web projects and in-house tools.

Education

Udacity

Tech Entrepreneur Nanodegree, 2015 – 2016

National Mining University, Dnepropetrovsk, Ukraine

Bachelor, Management, Economics, 2004 – 2008

Skills

Languages

PHP, Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks

Zend, Laravel, Sinatra, AngularJS

WebServices

SOAP, REST, JSON API, oAuth

Databases & Search

MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Solr

Testing

PHPUnit, Rspec, Cucumber, Selenium, Jasmine

Continuous Integration

Bamboo, Capistrano, TravisCI